so let's first look at the methods that
try to reduce hit time some of the
methods are pretty obvious like reduce
the cache size that's gonna improve the
hit time but this is bad for the miss
rate so the overall aim at might not
actually be improved because we are
gonna improve the hit time but we're
gonna increase the miss rate and thus
pay more of those miss penalties that
are quite large so we can do this but we
have to do it carefully to balance the
miss rate and the hit time the next
simple method is reduce the cache
associativity this is gonna make the
cache faster because we need to search
in only one or few places for a block on
a hit but this is also bad for miss rate
for similar reasons when we reduce
associativity we are creating more
misses because blocks are gonna start
having conflicts and start kicking each
other out even though they might coexist
peacefully in a more associative cache
so the last simple methods for reducing
hit time involve overlapping the cache
hit with another hit overlapping the
cache hit with the TLB access optimizing
the lookups so that common cases get
faster without sacrificing the uncommon
case too much and maintaining the
replacement state in the cache more
quickly so on hits we need to update
some state that we will need later for
replacements and we can make this more
efficient so we will look at four
methods that are trying to achieve these
four things here